Curriculum Vitae Seth Ouma Okeyo

Date of birth: 29th March 1986

Address: P.O. Box 78477-00507, Nairobi

Cell-phone +254727389149, +254762027386, +254727982995.

E-mail: okeyoseth@gmail.com/okeyoseth@yahoo.com/seth.okeyo@strathmore.edu

Languages: English, Kiswahili, and Dholuo.

PERSONAL PROFILE

I have over 10 years of work experience in clinical research area, doing data management, analysis, information and data management systems management and administration. I also have vast experience in management of research projects. I take my work very seriously and have a heightened awareness of ethics and professionalism. I am able to develop and maintain an excellent working relationship with colleagues and I do my work with minimal supervision, meet timelines and give best to attainable quality.

EMPLOYMENT RECORD

December 2020 - Current.

Research Data Scientist / Bioinformatician at Kenya Medical Research Institute (KEMRI), Center for Virus Research.

- Contribute to designing research projects that apply valid scientific techniques and use information obtained from baselines or historical data to structure uncompromised and efficient analyses.
- Assist in planning data collection methods for specific projects and determine the types and sizes of sample groups to be used.
- Assist in adapting statistical methods to solve specific problems in biomedicine and other relevant fields.
- Help develop and test experimental designs, sampling techniques, and analytical methods
- Provide support for analysis and interpretation of statistical data to identify significant differences in relationships among sources of information.
- Participate in developing and understanding of fields to which statistical methods are to be applied to determine whether methods and results are appropriate.
- Help in evaluating sources of information to determine any limitations in terms of reliability or usability.
- Contribute to the evaluating the statistical methods and procedures used to obtain data to ensure validity, applicability, efficiency, and accuracy.
- Helps identify relationships and trends in data, as well as any factors that could affect the results of the research.
- Participate in preparing data for processing by organizing information, checking for any inaccuracies, and adjusting and weighing the raw data.

- Contribute to reporting results of statistical analyses, including information in the form of graphs, charts, and tables.
- Help examine theories, such as those of probability and inference, to discover mathematical bases for new or improved methods of obtaining and evaluating numerical data.
- Support in presentation of statistical and non-statistical results using charts, bullets, and graphs in meetings or conferences to audiences such as clients, peers, and students.
- Assist in the processing of large amounts of data for statistical modeling and graphic analysis, using computers.

January 2019 to September 2020.

Lab Data Analyst and Project Assistant at US Army Research Directorate, Walter Reed Project. Kenya Medical Research Institute —Department of Emerging Infectious diseases (DEID).

- Develop and review Standard Operating Procedures for data management
- Transcribe primary and laboratory study data into a computerized database
- Participate in the data cleaning procedures
- Perform data analysis and provide as needed data summaries and reports
- Develop and use electronic databases such as Excel and Access
- Complete, review and archive paper documents with accuracy.
- File and retrieve study documents as required
- Maintain confidentiality of study participants
- Provide administrative support functions to the AMR PI and staff.
- Assist in the procurement and receipt of supplies and reagents and track deliveries in consultation with lab procurement officer.
- Prepare (print and copy) study documents as directed and ensure sites have all appropriate study documents
- Order and receive specific study supplies from procurement
- Write minutes for laboratory meetings and file appropriately
- Maintain records relating to the handling of documents and study data
- Coordinate shipment of supplies and material to study sites
- Organize and coordinate travel and logistics for AMR staff and visitors
- Able to interpret and apply rules, regulations, and guidelines.

April 2014 to December 2018.

Clinical Research Data Management Officer Drugs for Neglected Diseases Initiative, Africa

- Studies database design and implementation
- Query Management set up and implementation
- Installation, configuration and training users on DHIS2 for Study Surveillance
- Development of electronic Case Report Forms
- Data Query raising and reconciliation
- Data Back up and retrieval

- Supervision of Data entry clerks
- Training the data entry clerks on data entry in OpenClinica

September 2010 to April 2014

Clinical Research Data Management Assistant Drugs for Neglected Diseases Initiative, Africa

- Data entry
- Case report Forms development for data collection
- Data back up and archiving
- OpenClinica Installation and configuration
- Computer systems installation and maintenance

May to August 2010

Systems user Trainer and Support Cardiff Systems LTD, Nairobi Kenya

- System User training
- System Set-up and implementation Database development
- End-user support and troubleshooting

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

MSc. Information Technology, Business Intelligence Major 2021: Strathmore University, Nairobi Kenya.

BSc. Computer Information Systems 2014: Kenya Methodist University.

Diploma in Computer Studies 2009: The Technical University of Kenya.

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education KCSE 2005: Omboga Secondary School, Kendu-Bay. Attained Mean Grade B (Plain).

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education KCPE 2000: Kamolo Primary School, Kendu-Bay. Scored 421marks out of 700.

Analytics on SAS, November 2024: Great Learning Academy Online

Leadership and Management in Health 26th September to 5th December 2021: *University of Washington (UW) Seattle, USA.*

Evidence Informed Decision Making (EIDM), 22nd to 26th November 2021: Kenya Medical Research Institute, Resource Development & Knowledge Management Center.

Data Management, Analysis and Graphics using STATA and SPSS Training 23rd to 27th September 2019: *Indepth Research Services, Nairobi, Kenya.*

DHIS2 Fundamentals Training 27th May 2016: Kampala Uganda.

DHIS2 Information Use Training 03rd June 2016: Kampala Uganda.

Introduction to Good Clinical Practice 31st October to 1st November 2015: MRC, Khartoum Sudan.

Good Clinical Practice 3rd to 4th March 2016: Nairobi Kenya.

OpenClinica Central User Training 2nd to 5th June 2015: Amsterdam, the Netherlands.

Data Management, Quality, and Control 25th to 29th June 2012: Regional East African Center for Health Informatics, AMPATH, MTRH, Eldoret Kenya.

Data Management for Clinical Research 20th June 2012: Global Health Trials E-Learning.

STATA, SPSS, EPI-INFO for data management. 2011: Drugs for Neglected diseases initiative data Center, On-Job training.

PostgreSQL, **MySQL** databases administration 2011: Drugs for Neglected diseases initiative data Center, On-Job training.

Professional Communication Training. 18th March 2016: Global Burness, Nairobi Kenya.

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

6th to 9th November 2016(Lusaka Zambia) European and Developing Countries Clinical Trials Partnership Presented: Implementation of DHIS2 tracker application in Visceral Surveillance.

16th to 20th May 2017(Toledo Spain) 6th World Congress on Leishmaniasis. Presented: Implementation of DHIS2 tracker application in Visceral Surveillance

PUBLICATIONS

Okeyo, S., Omollo, R., Kimutai, R., Ochieng, M., & Egondi, T. (2017). PILOTING DHIS2 SYSTEM IN VISCERAL LEISHMANIASIS SURVEILLANCE. *BMJ Global Health*, 2(Suppl 2). https://gh.bmj.com/content/2/suppl_2/a64.3.abstract

Okeyo, S. O. (2021). A Prototype for profit maximization using Apriori data mining algorithm: case of Kula Kona restaurant (Doctoral dissertation, Strathmore University). https://su-plus.strathmore.edu/handle/11071/12936

Omollo, R., Ochieng, M., Mutinda, B., Omollo, T., Owiti, R., Okeyo, S., & Edwards, T. (2014). Innovative approaches to clinical data management in resource limited settings using open-source technologies. *PLoS neglected tropical diseases*, 8(9), e3134.

https://journals.plos.org/plosntds/article?id=10.1371/journal.pntd.0003134

Kirigi, G., Juma, R., Otieno, P., Omollo, R., Sulleh, A., Mutai, B. C., & Muiruri, S. (2019). Cotrimoxazole prophylaxis impact on Cd4+ cells & infection reduction in HAART naïve HIV infected adults in our urban population, Kenya. *African Journal of Health Sciences*, 32(1), 18-26. https://www.ajol.info/index.php/ajhs/article/view/184947

OTHER INTERESTS

- Training users and administration of Information systems
- Programming and systems development
- Reading, Singing, and Travelling

REFEREES

Dr. Samoel Ashimosi Khamadi, BSc, MSc, MPh, MBA, PhD

Deputy Director- Director Centre for Virus Research, Kenya Medical Research Institute

M: +254 722 807 841, Phone: (254) (020) 2722541, Skype: @skhamadi, <u>skhamadi@kemri.go.ke</u>, <u>skhamadi@gmail.com</u>;

P.O. Box 54840-00200 Nairobi Kenya

Dr. Monique Wasunna, MBChB, MSc, Ph.D., DTM&H, DLSHTM, FRSHTM

Director, Drugs for Neglected Diseases initiative, Africa Regional Office - Nairobi

Centre for Clinical Research, Kenya Medical Research Institute

P.O. Box 20778 KNH 00202, Nairobi, KENYA, africa@dndi.org.

Tel. +254-20-2730076, +254724255274

Dr. Raymond Omollo, Ph.D.

Clinical Research Statistician and Head of Data Center, Drugs for Neglected Diseases Initiative P.O. Box. 20778-00202, Nairobi

Cell: +254722588525 / +254734276516 romollov@yahoo.co.uk

Dr. Bernard Shibwabo, Ph.D.

Director, Research & Postgraduate Studies, Strathmore University, Nairobi Kenya.

Email: bshibwabo@strathmore.edu |

Office Tel: +254 (0) 703 034135 Ext: 2135 Mobile: +254724997911